Aaron Ziegelman Foundation collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Aaron Ziegelman Foundation collection 1931-2003
AFC 2003/002
Aaron Ziegelman Foundation
approximately 23,599 items
70 sound cassettes: analog
153 videocassettes (Betacam SP and Betacam SP Mega): sound, color
144 videocassettes (VHS and VHS-C): sound, color; 1/2 in.
8 videocassettes (Hi-8): sound, color
1 film reel (8 mm)
circa 2200 photographs: black and white, color; various sizes
23 artifacts
25 linear feet
10 volumes
31 floppy disks; 3 1/2 in.
4 zip disks
2 discs (CD): optical
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of audio and video recordings of oral histories conducted from 1994-2000 with family members of people who lived in Luboml, Poland (now in Ukraine) between World War I and World War II.
Provenance
Aaron Ziegelman Foundation; Donation; 2002-2003.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Access and Restrictions
The Aaron Ziegelman Foundation collection is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
In 1994, Aaron Ziegelman organized a research project that engaged archivists, anthropologists and historians in the collection, preservation and analysis of information about Jewish life in his birthplace, Luboml, a shtetl (market town) in Poland, whose Jewish community was destroyed in World War II. Luboml, Libivne in Yiddish, is now within the national borders of Ukraine. This documentary collection resulted in a major traveling exhibition, a book, and a documentary film about everyday life in Luboml during the years between World War I and World War II.
Scope and Content
Collection of audio and video recordings of oral histories conducted from 1994-2000 with family members of people who lived in Luboml, Poland (now in Ukraine) between World War I and World War II. With transcripts of these interviews; original photographs; photographs copied from the personal archives of these family members and from other archives; original passports, immigration papers, letters (including letters of the Eiger and Ziegelman families), product labels, a few artifacts, one original 8 mm film shot in Luboml, circa 1932; and transparencies of maps of Luboml. The collection includes video and audio footage from the production of the documentary film Luboml: My Heart Remembers (2002), with video footage of various visits to Luboml; the manuscript for the book Luboml: The Memorial Book of a Vanished Shtetl (1997), and various files regarding the exhibition Remembering Luboml: Images of a Jewish Community.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into five series. Series 1: Manuscripts are divided into nine subseries of administrative materials that were used by the Luboml Exhibition Project office. Series 2: Interviews on audiocassettes which were conducted between the years of 1973-2001. Series 3: Photographic prints document the history of Luboml before its untimely destruction. Series 4: Moving Images contain various interviews and documentaries pertaining to life in Luboml. Series 5: Adminsitrative files for the Luboml Project. Series 6: The Luboml Exhibition Project collected donations from Luboml survivors and their descendants. These items were divided into what the organization classified as an artifact or a photograph. This distinction is not clearcut as there are some photographs within the artifacts. As a family donated material, they were assigned a number proceeded by an "A." Series 7: Publications pertaining to Jewish culture.
There are twelve moving images MV284-296 which may or may not be duplicates of the moving images series items.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Ziegelman, Aaron, 1928-; Ziegelman, Aaron, 1928- Luboml: my heart remembers.
Organizations
Aaron Ziegelman Foundation
Subjects
Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945)--Ukraine--Li︠u︡bomlʹ.; Jews--Ukraine--Li︠u︡bomlʹ--History.
Places
Li︠u︡bomlʹ (Ukraine)--Ethnic relations.; Li︠u︡bomlʹ (Ukraine)--Social life and customs.
Titles
Sefer yizkor li-ḳehilat Luboml. English.
Form/Genre
Artifacts.; Documentary films.; Interviews.; Manuscripts for publication.; Manuscripts.; Maps.; Oral histories.; Sound recordings.; Video recordings.
Container List
- Series 1: Manuscripts
  - Finding Aid (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Subseries 1: Fred Wasserman Research
      - Jerusalem Research, Fred Wasserman Research, undated, 11 leaves (Box-folder 1/2)
        The manuscript materials are in English and Polish.
      - Jewish Historical Institute, Fred Wasserman Research, Undated, 56 leaves (Box-folder 1/3)
      - Jewish Museum, 1962-1997, 29 leaves (Box-folder 1/4)
      - Luboml - Jewish National and University Library, 1995-1996, 2 leaves (Box-folder 1/5)
        The manuscript materials are in English.
      - Luboml - Jewish Telegraphic Agency, 1987, 11 leaves (Box-folder 1/6)
      - Luboml - Jewish Week Announcement, 1995, 22 leaves (Box-folder 1/7)
      - Judson Art Warehouse, 1994-1995, 29 leaves (Box-folder 1/8)
      - Karp, Boris, 1992-1993, 8 leaves (2 color prints) (Box-folder 1/9)
        The manuscript materials are in English and Russian.
      - Kehillath Shalom, 1996, 43 leaves (16 color prints) (Box-folder 1/10)
      - Konin (New York Times Book Review), 1996, 3 leaves (Box-folder 1/11)
      - Kowalchuk Case, 198 leaves (Box-folder 1/12)
      - U.S. v. Kowalchuck (Folder 1 of 7), F.O.I.A. Request: 1st Phase, 1983-1990, 168 leaves (Box-folder 1/13)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Polish and German.
      - U.S. v. Kowalchuck (Folder 2 of 7), F.O.I.A. Request: 1st Phase, 1942, 1980-1990, 131 leaves (Box-folder 1/14)
        The manuscript materials are in English and German.
      - U.S. v. Kowalchuck (Folder 3 of 7), F.O.I.A. Request: 1st Phase, 1941, 1981, 156 leaves (Box-folder 2/15)
      - U.S. v. Kowalchuck (Folder 4 of 7), F.O.I.A. Request: 1st Phase, 1941-1945, 198 leaves (Box-folder 2/16)
      - U.S. v. Kowalchuck (Folder 5 of 7), F.O.I.A. Request: 1st Phase, 1981, 182 leaves (Box-folder 2/17)
        The manuscript materials are in English, German and Polish.
      - U.S. v. Kowalchuck (Folder 6 of 7), F.O.I.A. Request: 1st Phase, 1979-1981, 98 leaves (Box-folder 2/18)
      - U.S. v. Kowalchuck (Folder 7 of 7), F.O.I.A. Request: 1st Phase, 1949, 1975, 1981, 264 leaves (Box-folder 2/19)
      - Libivner Voliner Benevolent Society, 1981, 1996, 80 leaves (Box-folder 2/20)
      - Luboml Loan Forms, 1994-1995, 12 leaves (Box-folder 3/21)
        The manuscript materials are in English
      - Map Duplication Services Information, 1996-1999, 20 leaves (Box-folder 3/22)
      - Luboml - Maps, Fred Wasserman Research, Undated, 41 leaves (Box-folder 3/23)
        The manuscript materials are in English, German, Polish and Ukrainian.
      - Luboml - Memoirs, 1977, ca. 1980, 23 leaves (Box-folder 3/24)
      - Michael Goldberg Testimony, 1985, 1996, 119 leaves (Box-folder 3/25)
        The manuscript materials are in English and Yiddish.
      - Richard Rozen Testimony, 1947, 72 leaves (Box-folder 3/26)
      - Cindy Miller Design Group, 1991-1996, 36 leaves (Box-folder 3/27)
      - Moment: The Jewish Magazine for the 90's, 1995-1996, 120 leaves (Box-folder 3/28)
      - Museum of Jewish Heritage (Folder 1 of 2), 1995-1996, 155 leaves (Box-folder 3/29)
      - Museum of Jewish Heritage Previous Dinners (Folder 2 of 2), 1991, 1994, 237 leaves (Box-folder 3/30)
      - Schreiber, Nava, 1991, 1992, 1994, 1 page (Box-folder 3/31)
      - Nernets, Rita, 1994, 14 leaves (Box-folder 3/32)
      - Luboml - Oral History Scripts, 1991-1995, 14 leaves (Box-folder 3/33)
      - Poddebski, Henryk, Polish Photographer, 1994, 5 leaves (Box-folder 3/34)
        The manuscript materials are in English, German, Polish, Ukrainian and Yiddish.
      - Luboml - Outreach, 1996, 84 leaves (Box-folder 3/35)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Polish and Hebrew.
      - Luboml - Outreach, Cemeteries, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 3/36)
      - Permission Form - Beth Hatefutsoth Photo Archive, 1995 (Box-folder 3/37)
      - Luboml - Joint Distribution Committee, 1994, 41 leaves (Box-folder 3/38)
      - Permissions Photo Duplication Agreement Drafts, 1920-1921, 8 leaves (Box-folder 3/39)
      - Pinkas ha-Kehillot/Book of Communities, Poland, 1995, 15 leaves (Box-folder 3/40)
        The manuscript materials are in English and Hebrew.
      - Luboml - History - General, Undated, 126 leaves (Box-folder 3/41)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Polish and Ukrainian.
      - Luboml - History - Education/Youth, 1884-1995, 17 leaves (Box-folder 3/42)
      - Luboml - History - Economic Life, 1934, 23 leaves (Box-folder 3/43)
      - Luboml - History - Holocaust - Documents - Archives - Tetimonials (Folder 1 of 2), 1772-1938, 105 leaves (Box-folder 3/44)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Ukrainian, Russian, German and Hebrew.
      - Luboml - History - Holocaust - Documents - Archives - Testimonials (Folder 2 of 2), 1945-1995, 179 leaves (Box-folder 3/45)
        The manuscript materials are in English, German, Russian, Ukrainian and Polish.
      - Holocaust - Various Articles, 1932-1995, 48 leaves (Box-folder 3/46)
      - Holocaust Memorial Museum, 1995-1996, 84 leaves (Box-folder 3/47)
        The manuscript materials are in English, German and Russian.
      - Imageering Group, 1994-1996, 18 leaves (Box-folder 4/48)
      - Imperial War Museum, 1996, 23 leaves (Box-folder 4/49)
      - Israel Trip, 1996, 23 leaves (Box-folder 4/50)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Yiddish and Hebrew.
      - Jabotinsky Institute, 1994, 7 leaves (Box-folder 4/51)
      - Luboml Online (Jewish Community Online), 1964, 1969, 91 leaves (Box-folder 5/52)
      - Museum of Jewish Heritage Exhibit (Folder 1 of 3), 1995-1997, 92 leaves (Box-folder 5/53)
      - Museum of Jewish Heritage Exhibit (Folder 2 of 3), 1996-1997, 116 leaves (Box-folder 5/54)
      - Museum of Jewish Heritage Exhibit (Folder 3 of 3), 1995, 119 leaves (Box-folder 5/55)
      - Aaron Ziegelman at the Museum of Jewish Heritage Dinner Exhibition, 1995, 93 leaves (1 black and white print) (Box-folder 5/56)
      - Museum of Jewish Heritage - Venue Talks, 1995, 33 leaves (Box-folder 5/57)
      - Museum of Jewish Heritage - Journal Page, 1995-1996, 18 leaves (Box-folder 5/58)
      - Museum of Jewish Heritage - Dinner Page, 1995, 11 leaves (Box-folder 5/59)
      - Museum of Jewish Heritage - 1996 Dinner, 1996, 128 leaves (Box-folder 5/60)
        The manuscript materials are in English and French.
      - Shalom Foundation - Warsaw, 1996, 23 leaves (Box-folder 5/61)
      - Sh'ma: A Journal of Jewish Responsibility. "Finding Libivne," April 14, 1995-1997, 83 leaves (Box-folder 6/62)
      - Siegel, Steve, 1995, 2 leaves (Box-folder 6/63)
      - SOROS Foundation, 1994, 2 leaves (Box-folder 6/64)
      - Satsuk Diary, 1995, 21 leaves (4 color prints) (Box-folder 6/65)
        The manuscript materials are in English and Ukrainian.
      - Spielberg, Steven - Shoah Visual History Foundation, 1992, 9 leaves (Box-folder 6/66)
      - Luboml Synagogue, 1996, 18 leaves (Box-folder 6/67)
      - Luboml Postage Stamps - History, 1962, 1990-1991, 31 leaves (Box-folder 6/68)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Ukrainian, Polish, German, Yiddish and Hebrew.
      - Testimonials, 1993-1997, 7 leaves (Box-folder 6/69)
      - Teutsh, David - Reconstructionist Rabbinical College, 1995-1997, 8 leaves (Box-folder 6/70)
      - Translators, 1995, 2 leaves (Box-folder 6/71)
      - US Commission for the Preservation of American Heritage Abroad, 1996, 13 leaves (Box-folder 6/72)
      - Warsaw Research and Information, 1994-1995, 21 leaves (Box-folder 6/73)
      - Luboml - Status Report - Master, 1992-1996, 49 leaves (Box-folder 6/74)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Polish, Hebrew and Yiddish.
      - Luboml Video, 1994, 92 leaves (Box-folder 6/75)
    - Subseries 2: Resesarch Trip / Luboml Visit
      - Planning, 1994-1995, 84 leaves (Box-folder 7/76)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Polish and Russian.
      - Press, 1995-1996, 57 leaves (Box-folder 7/77)
      - Artifact Return and Retrieval: Research Trip / Luboml Visit, 1995-1996, 51 leaves (Box-folder 7/78)
      - Itinerary, Addresses, Travel Documents, Telephone Numbers, 1995-1996, 44 leaves (Box-folder 7/79)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Russian, Ukrainian and Polish.
      - Weiner, Miriam (Folder 1 of 3), 1995, 69 leaves (Box-folder 7/80)
      - Weiner, Miriam (Folder 2 of 3), 1995, 113 leaves (Box-folder 7/81)
      - Weiner, Miriam (Folder 3 of 3), 1995, 80 leaves (Box-folder 7/82)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Ukrainian, Russian and Polish.
      - Luboml Visit Background - Don't Take Along, 1995, 59 leaves (Box-folder 7/83)
      - Ziegelman, Aaron (English, Russian), 1995, 40 leaves (Box-folder 7/84)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Russian, Ukrainian and Yiddish.
      - Photo Processing Procedures, 1995, 2 leaves (Box-folder 7/85)
      - Video, Personal Release Forms, Undated, 11 leaves (Box-folder 7/86)
      - Video Releases - Filled In, Undated, 15 leaves (Box-folder 7/87)
      - Signed Foreign Permission Forms, 1995-1996, 17 leaves (Box-folder 7/88)
      - Signed Permissions - Museum of Jewish Heritage, 1995-1996, 36 leaves (Box-folder 7/89)
      - Signed Permissions - Ukraine, 1995, 14 leaves (Box-folder 7/90)
    - Luboml Exhibition Project Documentation
      - Stationery, 1995-1996, 70 leaves (Box-folder 8/91)
      - Luboml - People Follow-up, 1995, 32 leaves (Box-folder 8/92)
      - Luboml - To do, 1994-1997, 70 leaves (Box-folder 8/93)
      - Luboml - Pending, 1994-1997, 18 leaves (Box-folder 8/94)
      - Old Lists and Memos, 1996, 96 leaves (Box-folder 8/95)
        The manuscript materials are in English and Spanish.
      - Notes - Fred Wasserman, 1997-1998, 38 leaves (Box-folder 8/96)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Ukrainian, Polish and Yiddish.
      - YIVO Institute for Jewish Research, 1945-1995, 42 leaves (Box-folder 8/97)
      - Freudenheim, Tom / YIVO Institute for Jewish Research, 1994-1996, 9 leaves (Box-folder 8/98)
      - Yedi’ot Aharonot Announcement, 1995-1997, 5 leaves (Box-folder 8/99)
      - Meetings with Aaron Ziegelman, 1994, 26 leaves (Box-folder 8/100)
      - Firsthand Accounts: Chernyak, Rita, 1994-1995, 37 leaves (Box-folder 8/101)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Russian and Ukrainian.
      - Firsthand Accounts: Dunietz, Edward, 1996, 17 leaves (Box-folder 8/102)
      - Firsthand Accounts: Eiger, Nathan, 1992, 1 leaf (Box-folder 8/103)
      - Firsthand Accounts: Pachter, Esther, 1995, 8 leaves (Box-folder 8/104)
      - Firsthand Accounts: Plotnik, Riwa, 1984, 1994-1995, 13 leaves (Box-folder 8/105)
      - Firsthand Accounts: Posner, Clara, 1996, 62 leaves (Box-folder 8/106)
      - Firsthand Account: Sobel, Nathan, 1988, 112 leaves (Box-folder 8/107)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Yiddish, Hebrew, Polish and Russian.
      - Firsthand Accounts: Ziegelman, Aaron (Folder 1 of 2), 1991-1996, 69 leaves (Box-folder 8/108)
      - Firsthand Accounts: Ziegelman, Aaron (Folder 2 of 2), 1988-1997, 93 leaves (Box-folder 8/109)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Polish, Russian, Yiddish and Ukrainian.
      - Luboml Descendents and Correspondence, 1985-1997, 62 leaves (Box-folder 9/110)
      - The National Jewish Center for Learning and Leadership (CLAL), 1994-1997, 8 leaves (Box-folder 9/111)
      - S. An-Sky (An-Ski), Solomon Zangwil Rapaport, 1998, 25 leaves (Box-folder 9/112)
      - Axelrod, Toby (Folder 1 of 2), 1994-1995, 58 leaves (16 colors prints, 5 negative strips) (Box-folder 9/113)
      - Axelrod, Toby (Folder 2 of 2), 1987-1997, 108 leaves (Box-folder 9/114)
      - Responses to Toby Axelrod's Article, September 1995, 1987-1997, 66 leaves (Box-folder 9/115)
      - Berman, Brad (Judah L. Magnes Museum), 1995-1997, 39 leaves (Box-folder 9/116)
      - Green, Joseph (Yiddish Filmmaker), 1995, 3 leaves (Box-folder 9/117)
      - Polish Business Directory (Photocopies), 1996, 17 leaves (Box-folder 9/118)
        The manuscript materials are in Polish.
      - Beth Hatefutsoth (Folder 1 of 3), 1930, 38 leaves (Box-folder 9/119)
      - Beth Hatefutsoth (Folder 2 of 3), 1996-1997, 3 leaves (61 color prints and 4 negatives strips) (Box-folder 9/120)
      - Beth Hatefutsoth (Folder 3 of 3), 1994-1995, 68 leaves (Box-folder 9/121)
      - Council of American Jewish Museums (CAJM), 1994-1996, 8 leaves (Box-folder 9/122)
      - Council of American Jewish Museums (CAJM), 1995 Conference, 1996-1997, 75 leaves (Box-folder 9/123)
      - Council of American Jewish Museums (CAJM), 1996 Conference, 1995 (Box-folder 9/124)
      - Council of American Jewish Museums (CAJM), 1997 Conference, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 9/125)
      - Center for Jewish Art, 1996-1997, 4 leaves (Box-folder 9/126)
      - Central Archives for the History of the Jewish People, 1994-1995, 21 leaves (Box-folder 9/127)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Hebrew and Russian.
      - Luboml Chronology, 1994, 3 leaves (Box-folder 10/128)
      - Potential Primary Sources, 1366-1990's, 1 leaf (Box-folder 10/129)
      - Luboml Flyers, Undated, 5 leaves (Box-folder 10/130)
      - Roots, Shtetls, Holocaust, Undated, 14 leaves (Box-folder 10/131)
      - Donors, 1990-1996, 9 leaves (Box-folder 10/132)
      - Dead Ends, 1994-1995, 20 leaves (Box-folder 10/133)
      - Designers, 1994-1996, 20 leaves (Box-folder 10/134)
      - Douglas/Gallagher, 1996, 44 leaves (Box-folder 10/135)
      - Eastern Europe Research Information, 1995, 50 leaves (Box-folder 10/136)
      - Powiat Lubomelski (Polish Untranslated), 1990-1995, 83 leaves (Box-folder 10/137)
      - Buenos Aires Research, 1936, 10 leaves (Box-folder 10/138)
        The manuscript materials are in Spanish and Yiddish.
      - Galicia Jews, 1988-1989, 1997, 43 leaves (Box-folder 10/139)
      - Ukranian Culture, 1907, 1971, 1983, 1989, 44 leaves (Box-folder 10/140)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Cyrillic, Polish, German and Yiddish.
      - State Archives of the Russian Federation (GARF) (Folder 1 of 3), 58 leaves (Box-folder 10/141)
      - State Archives of the Russian Federation (GARF) (Folder 2 of 3), 123 leaves (Box-folder 10/142)
      - State Archives of the Russian Federation (GARF) (Folder 3 of 3), 1943 (Box-folder 10/143)
        The manuscript materials are in Russian.
      - Polish Jewry - Contemporary, 1943 (Box-folder 10/144)
      - Polish Jewry - Historical, 1996, 30 leaves (Box-folder 10/145)
      - Polish Akademia Instituit Sztuki, 1964, 1977, 34 leaves (Box-folder 10/146)
      - Salzmann, Laurence (Photographer/Filmmaker), 1995-1996, 11 leaves (Box-folder 10/147)
      - Schwartz, Fred (Haberfield House Foundation), 1995, 30 leaves (Box-folder 10/148)
      - Borodulin, Nikolay (Kovalchuk information from Russian and Ukranian Archives), Undated, 53 leaves (Box-folder 11/149)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Ukrainian and Russian.
      - Translators, 1995, 32 leaves (Box-folder 11/150)
      - Sinkoff, Nancy (Translator), 1995-1998, 10 leaves (Box-folder 11/151)
      - Synagoge am Michelsberg Brochure, 1995, 1 leaf (Box-folder 11/152)
        The manuscript material is in German.
      - Ukranian Research Material, Undated, 12 leaves (Box-folder 11/153)
        The manuscript materials are in English, French, Russian and Ukrainian.
      - Exhibition Plan - Family Album, 1970-2001, 4 leaves (Box-folder 11/154)
      - Exhibition Plan - List of Photographs, Undated, 2 leaves (Box-folder 11/155)
      - Exhibition Plan - Copies Sent, Undated, 78 leaves (Box-folder 11/156)
      - Exhibition Plan - Corrections (Folder 1 of 6), 1995-1997, 35 leaves (Box-folder 11/157)
      - Exhibition Plan - Corrections (Folder 2 of 6), Undated, 41 leaves (Box-folder 11/158)
      - Exhibition Plan - Corrections from Ruby Tallis (Folder 3 of 6), 1995, 32 leaves (Box-folder 11/159)
      - Exhibition Plan - Corrections (Folder 4 of 6), 1995, 32 leaves (Box-folder 11/160)
      - Exhibition Plan - Corrections (Folder 5 of 6), 1995, 32 leaves (Box-folder 11/161)
      - Exhibition Plan - Corrections (Folder 6 of 6), 1995, 88 leaves (Box-folder 11/162)
      - Exhibition Plan - Outdated Masters, 1995, 8 leaves (Box-folder 11/163)
      - Exhibition Plan Masters - Photography, 1995, 33 leaves (Box-folder 11/164)
      - Exhibition Plan Masters - Color Laser Copy, Undated, 68 leaves (Box-folder 11/165)
      - Exhibition Plan Masters - Photographs, Undated, 45 leaves (Box-folder 11/166)
      - Exhibition Plan Masters - Bound Copy, Undated, 68 leaves (Box-folder 11/167)
      - Programming for Luboml Exhibition, Undated, 15 leaves (Box-folder 11/168)
      - Aaron Ziegelman's Article on Trip to Luboml, 1984-1995, 62 leaves (Box-folder 12/169)
      - Luboml Quotes, 1995, 42 leaves (Box-folder 12/170)
      - Reconstructionist Synagogue of the North Shore, 1995, 10 leaves (Box-folder 12/171)
      - Mailing Lists - Luboml Visit, 1996, 76 leaves (Box-folder 12/172)
      - Mailing Lists - Donor Addresses, 1995-1996, 99 leaves (Box-folder 12/173)
      - Mailing Lists - Israel Addresses, 1995, 17 leaves (Box-folder 12/174)
      - Mailing Lists - General, 1995, 139 leaves (Box-folder 12/175)
      - Luboml Exhibition Project Online, 1995-1997, 72 leaves (Box-folder 12/176)
      - America Online (AOL) Family Album, 1996-1997, 18 leaves (Box-folder 12/177)
      - America Online (AOL) Religious and Family Life, Undated, 25 leaves (Box-folder 12/178)
      - America Online (AOL) Youth, Undated, 21 leaves (Box-folder 12/179)
      - America Online (AOL) Leaving Luboml, Undated, 6 leaves (Box-folder 12/180)
      - America Online (AOL) War and Return to Life, Undated, 18 leaves (Box-folder 12/181)
      - American Online (AOL) Our Shtetl, Undated, 23 leaves (Box-folder 12/182)
      - America Online (AOL) 2-D Artifacts, Undated, 21 leaves (Box-folder 12/183)
        The manuscript materials are in English, German Polish, Yiddish and Ukrainian.
      - America Online (AOL) 3-D Artifacts, Undated, 13 leaves (Box-folder 12/184)
      - Berman Associates - Communication Services, Undated, 40 leaves (Box-folder 12/185)
    - Subseries 3: Traveling Exhibitions
      - Exhibition Calendars, 1996-2003, 7 leaves (Box-folder 13/186)
      - Venues (Folder 1 of 2), 1996-1997, 53 leaves (Box-folder 13/187)
      - Venues (Folder 2 of 2), 1995-1998, 52 leaves (Box-folder 13/188)
      - City Athletic Club, New York, NY, January-February, 1995-1998, 32 leaves (29 color prints, 12 negative strips) (Box-folder 13/189)
      - The Gershman Y, Philadelphia, PA, February-April, 1997, 92 leaves (3 exhibit labels) (Box-folder 13/190)
      - The Gershman Y, Philadelphia, PA - Gallery, February-April, 56 leaves (37 color prints, 11 negative strips) (Box-folder 13/191)
      - The Gershman Y, Philadelphia, PA - Artifact Captions, February-April, 1997, 17 leaves (Box-folder 13/192)
      - The Gershman Y, Philadelphia, PA - Panel Captions, February-April, 1997, 30 leaves (Box-folder 13/193)
      - The Gershman Y, Philadelphia, PA - Installation Booklet, February - April, 1997, 37 leaves (Box-folder 13/194)
      - The Gershman Y, Philadelphia, PA - Ragone, Keith (Folder 1 of 2), February - April, 1997, 112 leaves (Box-folder 13/195)
        The manuscript materials are in English, Polish, Ukrainian and Yiddish.